我来给你描绘一下
Let me paint you a picture
一个没有怪物  没有恶魔
of a world without monsters or demons
一个再没有人会因为超自然生灵而死的世界
Of a world where no one has to die because of the supernatural.
一个新世界  一个更好的世界
Of a new world, a better world.
继续说
I'm listening.
(忆往昔)
你没有我的把柄
You have no hold on me.
加文  跟爸爸打个招呼啊
Gavin, honey, say hello to daddy.
-你怎么  -我知道些咒语  克劳力
- How did you... - I know a spell or two, Crowley.
你知道他得回去吧
You get that he's got to go back, right?
他的命运是登上去美国的轮船
his destiny is to board a ship bound for America.
那艘船会在暴风雨中沉没  无人生还
That ship went down in a storm. All hands were lost.
改变过去的任何一件事
you change any one thing in the past,
造成的连锁反应会影响之后的一切
the ripple effect impacts everything that follows.
该死  克劳力
Damn it, Crowley!
地狱王子是什么
What the hell is a Prince of Hell?
是最古老的恶魔
The oldest of the old demons.
路西法亲自转化了他们
Lucifer turned them himself.
他们是受训将军
They were trained to be generals,
带领恶魔大军与天堂作战
to lead demonic armies in the war against Heaven.
就像亚撒色
Like Azazel.
他们眼睛都一样
They even have his eyes.
知道我们是谁吗
You have any idea who we are?
我不在乎  我不在乎你们是谁
I don't care. I don't care who you are.
我甚至不在乎路西法要有娃了
I don't even care that Lucifer's got a bun in the oven.
这你也知道
You know about that?
我妹妹大衮  她对此颇为关切
My sister Dagon, she's taken an interest.
(如今)
(麻萨诸塞州  安多弗)
(六个月前)
[邪恶力量 第12季第13集]
好  继续查
Okay, well, stay on it.
有线索告诉我们
You get any leads, you let us know,
我们这边也会继续查
and we'll keep working it from our end.
谢谢  小卡
Thanks, Cass.
凯莉·克莱恩还不知所踪
So Kelly Kline is in the wind.
-毫无踪迹  -太好了
- No trace. - Great.
也不知道路西法的孩子什么时候会出世
No idea when Lucifer's kid is gonna pop,
或许已经出世了
if it hasn't already.
-那么我们基本上什么都没查到  -是啊
- So basically, we got nothin'. - Basically.
好  我们还有别的情况
All right. Well, we do have this other thing.
什么情况
What other thing?
来看看  爱荷华州得梅因一家博物馆
Check it out. Museum in Des Moines, Iowa.
一名教师的尸体在停车场被发现
A guy's body was found in the parking lot. A teacher.
他的舌头被拽了出来
His tongue had been ripped out.
他不是因此致死
Well, that didn't kill him.
是啊  但他死于内脏粉碎
No, but having his internal organs crushed did.
躯干没有明显损伤  没有入口伤
Uh, no obvious damage to the torso, no point of entry.
-巫师  -可能吧
- You thinkin' witch? - Maybe.
他几小时前还活得好好的
I mean, he was seen alive just a couple hours earlier,
在博物馆带学生参观
leading a student tour of the museum.
好久没见到妈妈了
Haven't seen Mom in a while.
或许她可以跟我们一起去
Maybe she'll wanna work with us on this.
玩具不错
Nice toy.
能完成任务
Gets the job done.
迪恩
Hey, Dean.
没事  就是...
Nothin', just, uh...
我在纽瓦克市外的一家旅馆
I'm at a motel outside Newark.
没什么特别的安排
No, no special plans.
就是付费电视  按摩
You know, pay-per-view, magic fingers,
好酒好菜
the uze.
谢谢你想到我  我...
Oh, it's so sweet of you to think of me. I...
被拔舌啊
Tongue ripped out.
我...
I, uh...
其实雷米尔那档子事后
I'm actually still sort of resting up
我还没完全缓过来
after that whole Ramiel thing.
但如果你们需要我
But if you need me...
真的
You sure?
好  那改日
Okay, rain check.
我爱你
Hey, I love you.
你真是会撒谎  玛丽
You're an excellent liar, Mary.
我还没跟我儿子说过我在跟你合作
I haven't told my sons I'm working with you.
我看出来了  我能理解
I gathered, and I understand.
萨姆和迪恩  不怎么喜欢我们
Sam and Dean aren't our... biggest fans.
是啊  因为你们折磨了他们
Yeah, 'cause you, uh, tortured them.
-这事我们说过了  -是啊
- We've been through that. - Right.
不是你  是你们的"乱来特工"
It wasn't you, it was your, uh, "rogue operative."
是啊
Exactly.
那么
So...
去喝一杯
drink?
你起初会抵抗的
Oh, you'll resist, at first.
但羞辱感会侵蚀你
But the humiliation will eat at you.
直到  最终
Until, finally,
彻底的无助感
you're worn down
会击垮你
by your utter helplessness.
你会喊我
And you will call me...
主人
Master.
你吹嘘自己无上的力量
You brag of your superior power.
天才比蛮力更胜一筹
Well, genius trumps brute force.
我找了十几个我最忠诚的手下去研究
I've had a dozen of my most loyal studying the cage
在分子层级上关押你的笼子
where you were held at the molecular level.
他们成功复制了材料
They managed to replicate the material.
做了那些锁链
They made those chains.
把你弄到这儿来  就是另一码事了
Getting you here...well, that was a different matter.
克劳力  还是帮倒忙
Crowley, still not helping.
听着  我们清楚自己在做什么
Listen, we know what we're talking about here.
我们查路西法很久了
We have been on Lucifer's trail for a long time.
那房间里的每个人显然都专注于
Everybody in the room was obviously focused
用妈妈的咒语把你送回笼子
on sending you back using Mother's spell.
除了我
Everybody except yours truly.
罗威娜  快
Rowena, now!
[咒语]
我修改了咒语
I managed to pervert that spell.
让你的灵体没有被送回笼子
So your essence wasn't sent back to the cage,
而是...
but instead,
我们几年前找到了你抛弃的皮囊
we found your discarded vessel a few years ago...
修复了它
...repaired it,
改进了它
improved it,
让它成为了适合真正的你的
making it a fitting final home
最终归宿
for the real you.
怎么
What?
没有坏坏的吐槽吗
No snarky, devilish comments?
你无话可说吗
You have nothing to say?
谢谢
Thanks?
如此费心
I mean, all that effort.
你本可把我关回笼子里  但没有
So you could've had me back in the cage, but no,
你想进行你可悲的小复仇
you needed your sad, little revenge.
你觉得这事会怎样结局
How do you think this is going to end?
对了  新家不错
Nice new digs, by the way.
挺舒服
Cozy.
听好  看来还有一起凶杀
Get this. It looks like there was another murder.
类似我们要去看的那起
It's just like the one we're checking up on.
-爱荷华州吗  -不  麻萨诸塞州  安多弗
- Iowa? - No, Andover, Massachusetts.
六个月前  女性
Six months ago. A woman.
尸体的状况是一样的
Body was found in the same condition.
她貌似也是老师
Looks like she was a teacher, too.
可惜妈妈不能来
Too bad Mom couldn't make it.
你说她太累了
You said she was too tired?
是啊
Yeah.
怎么了
What?
我不知道  就是...
I don't know, I just --
我觉得她好像有什么事
I feel like something's going on with her,
不肯说
and she ain't talkin' about it.
妈妈又猎魔了  这很辛苦的  你也知道
Mom's hunting again. That's a grind. You know that.
她就是需要点时间而已  迪恩
She just needs a little time, Dean. That's all.
是啊
Yeah.
(新英格兰沉船)
好了  你们上皮尔森先生的车  快走
Okay, you're in Mr. Peterson's van, guys. Come on.
(爱荷华州  得梅因)
我马上就回来
I'll be back out in one minute.
(新英格兰沉船  明星号)
再次感谢你见我们  奥乔亚博士
So thank you ygain for meeting with us, Dr. Ochoa.
不客气  探员  我...
Of course, Agent. I...
我们两天内发生了两起杀人案
We've had two murders in two days.
警方毫无头绪
The police have no idea what's going on, and --
所以我们来了嘛
Well, that's why we're here.
你说第二名被害人
Now you said victim number two brought some
带童子军来参观了
Timber Troopers through here, right?
16小时前他们就站在这里
16 hours ago, they were standing right where you are.
博物馆来了什么新藏品吗
Is there anything new to the museum?
在实验室
Well, here in the lab,
刚开箱了三件巡回展品
three traveling exhibits have been uncrated.
一件已经摆出来了  另两个还在做准备
One's already on display. The other two are being prepped.
奥乔亚博士
Dr. Ochoa?
-失陪  -没事
- Excuse me. - Sure.
好吧  那么
Okay, so...
包括麻省的那名被害人
including the Massachusetts vic,
总共两个老师  一个童子军领队
that is two teachers and one scout leader.
都是监督孩子的人
People who supervise kids.
这里挺闹啊
There's a lot of action in here.
好吧  我改投鬼一票了
Okay, well, I'm switching my vote from witch to ghost.
未必  博物馆有电磁场不是怪事
I don't know. EMF isn't that surprising at a museum.
这里到处是不安分的灵魂
They're always filled with ADHD spirits
和束缚他们的物件
and their tethers, you know?
好吧  如果凶犯是鬼魂
Okay, but if our killer is a chain rattler,
我们要怎么查明是哪一个
how we gonna figure out which one it is?
可以点了吗  亲爱的
Ready, honey?
就来点橙汁好了
Uh, just some orange juice, please.
小杯的
Small.
什么时候临盆
So, when you due?
我不知道
I have no idea.
听我一句
Well, take it from me,
生孩子前  你的人生是自己的
before kids, your life is yours.
等他们降生  你所熟悉的人生就结束了
Once they show up, life as you know it is over.
是啊
Yeah.
这事应该就是这样了
Pretty sure that's the way this is gonna go.
但是  等它出来后
But whenever it pops out,
你绝对会爱上那个小坏蛋的
you're totally gonna love the little devil.
阿芝特克人杀人不含糊
Aztecs were pretty serious about their killings.
阿芝特克鬼魂
Aztec ghost.
我喜欢
Yeah, I like that.
查到什么了
What you got?
是一艘双桅帆船  明星号上的
It's from a ship, um, a brigantine called The Star.
在新英格兰岸边因风暴沉没
Sunk in a storm off the New England coast.
是从一家
Currently on loan from
海事博物馆借来的  听好
the Maritime Museum in -- wait for it --
是麻省  安多弗的博物馆
Andover, Massachusetts.
-真的  -嗯
- Really? - Yeah.
1723年沉没于风暴
Sunk in a storm in 1723.
等等  这个我知道
W-wait a minute. I know something about something,
这艘船的事
about this ship.
当时它驶往新大陆
It was, uh, headed to the New World.
曾在苏格兰利斯停靠
Weighed anchor in Leith, Scotland.
利斯  对了
Leith. Yes.
加文·麦克劳德
Gavin MacLeod.
-就是这艘船  -克劳力儿子
- This was his ship. - Crowley's kid?
对
Yep.
抱歉  就是...
Sorry, it's just that...
你还真
Y-you -- you actually...
以为这样能成功
you seriously think this is gonna work?
这...
It's just, uh...
太可悲了
It's so sad.
希望你喜欢地板的味道
Hope you like the taste of floor.
地上有一块需要擦干净
There's a spot there needs scrubbing.
更糟的是
And worse,
你被打败时
you're not even gonna see it comin'
会措手不及
when you get taken down.
就凭你
By you?
还有我的骨血
And my flesh and blood.
是吗
Really?
你记得那位可爱的
You remember the lovely...
凯莉·克莱恩吧
Kelly Kline?
她把孩子打掉了
She got rid of that thing.
是吗
Did she now?
温家兄弟确保了
The Winchesters saw to it.
因为你永远能信任他们
Because they can always be trusted.
那对他们也有利
It was in their own self-interest.
有意思
Interesting.
因为我还能感觉到它
Because I can still feel it.
它的心脏
Its heart.
它的力量
Its power.
让我有些骄傲
Sort of makes me proud.
天堂之光的后代
A chip off the old ball of heavenly light,
懂吗
if you know what I mean.
电话
Phone.
-什么事  -帮个忙
- What do you want? - Need a favor.
你...要我...
You...need...
帮忙
You?
原来
Turns out
你和你弟弟白痴的表面下
that behind that whole moron facade,
是货真价实的白痴
you and your brother are, in fact, morons!
你们让路西法的私生子活了下来
You let Lucifer's love child live.
你怎么知道的
How do you even know about that?
我不需要向你解释
I don't owe you an explanation.
好吧  我猜现在不太合适
Okay, so I'm -- I'm guessing this isn't the best time
求你联络加文
to ask you to get in touch with Gavin
让我们跟他说话
so we can talk to him?
你疯了吗
Are you out of your minds?
克劳力
You know what, Crowley?
你让加文去生活在我们的时代
When you set Gavin free to live in our time
这可能搅和了余下的人类历史
and possibly screw up the rest of human history,
我们可没去追杀他
we didn't hunt him down, okay?
所以你欠我们的
So I think you owe us.
你和波波鹿
You and Bullwinkle
趁那玩意破壳而出前  解决麻烦
fix this mess before it hatches.
然后  或许我们还能谈谈我儿子
Then, maybe then, we'll talk about my son.
我的爸
Oh, my Dad.
我喜欢这点  我们都是单身父亲
I love that. You and I, both single fathers.
我现在挺需要关于当爹的建议
I could use a little Dad advice right about now.
什么时候允许孩子约会
When do you let 'em date?
(美国历史学会)
别推搡  女士们
No pushing, ladies.
在大巴上要像在博物馆里一样文明礼貌
Let's be as polite on the bus as we were in the museum.
同学们  不许占座
Class, no saving seats.
车上不许吃东西  莎朗
No food on the bus, Sharon.
知道了
Okay.
你们的故事太精彩了
Your little story's fascinating,
但你们说这事有我的好处
but you said there was something in this for me?
如果凶犯是鬼魂
If the killer is a ghost,
它可能束缚在了船上的什么东西上
it may be tethered to something on the ship.
我们需要关于船的情报
So we need intel on the vessel.
去办个图书证吧
Get a library card.
阿肯色州的事  你俩还欠我人情呢
You two still owe me for helping you in Arkansas.
坐下
Sit down.
我们认识一个有关于明星号第一手资料的人
We know of a guy who has firsthand knowledge of The Star.
那又如何
So?
如果你找到他
So, if you find him,
我们真的有你会喜欢的东西
we actually do have something that you'll like.
非常喜欢的
Like, really like.
这个目击者是谁
Who is this eyewitness?
离她远点
Get away from her!
她是我们的  恶魔
She's ours, Demon.
-有令在身  -不关我事
- Orders. - Not my problem.
不
No.
想活命就跟我走
Come with me if you wanna live.
我知道  你吓坏了
I get it. You're freaked.
但深呼吸  冷静
But take a breath. Chill.
你让那些人爆炸了
Y-you made those people explode.
再说一遍  他们不是人  而且他们在攻击你
Again, not people. And they were attacking you.
你说你是个恶魔
And you said you were a demon.
名号  标签
Titles, labels.
我是个恶魔  你是罗斯玛丽  怀着孩子
I'm a demon, you're Rosemary, complete with baby.
拜托
Please.
你们这些人类
You humans.
你们被洗脑太深
You've been fed so much propaganda.
主日学校是怎么讲路西法的
What did they teach you about Lucifer at Sunday School?
我猜猜  干草叉  角
Let me guess. Pitchforks? Horns?
他们提过他是个大天使吗
But did they mention he's an archangel?
曾是上帝最信任的人
Once one of God's most trusted?
你是什么...
What are you...
我都不知道你的名字呢
I don't even know your name.
大衮  我叫大衮
Dagon. It's Dagon.
听着  我只是想说  这事不是黑白分明的
Look, what I'm saying is it ain't all black and white,
非善即恶
good versus evil.
那些想杀你的"人"
Those "people" who were tryin' to kill you?
是天使
Angels.
没错
Yeah, that's right.
不像你想的那样是光晕加竖琴吧
Not quite the harps and halos you thought.
他们为什么想杀你呢
And why'd they want you dead?
因为你怀了一个无辜的孩子
Because you're carrying an innocent child.
我知道你害怕
I know you're scared.
别相信电影里的东西
Don't believe what you see in the movies.
没人生来就有善恶  养育才是关键
No one is born good or bad. It's all in the upbringing.
这个孩子  你的孩子
This child, your child...
他可以拯救我们所有人
he could save us all.
他
He?
你不知道
You didn't know.
我...
I...
不知道
No.
凯莉  天使  温家兄弟  那些好人
Kelly, the angels? The Winchesters? The good guys?
他们都想要你死
They want you dead.
但我可以保护你
But I can protect you.
我可以保护你儿子
I can protect your son.
你再也不用逃跑了
You don't have to run anymore.
-他来了  -嗯
- There he is. - Yep.
加文
Gavin.
你好  加文  见到你很高兴
Hey, Gavin. Good to see ya.
21世纪的生活怎么样
How's life in the 21st century treatin' ya?
还行
Oh, fine.
我父亲呢
Where's my father, then?
跟我们走走吧  加文
Walk with us, Gav.
-他病得多重  -那个嘛
- How sick is he? - About that...
我们可能夸张了一点
we might've exaggerated a little bit.
撒谎  我们撒谎了
Lied. We lied.
好吧  我们知道你单为我们是不会来的
Okay, well, we knew you wouldn't come if it was just us.
我们需要你帮忙  加文
We need your help, Gavin.
"帮忙"
"Help"?
-救命  -没事的
- Help! - Nah, we're fine.
听我们说完吧
Um, just hear us out, please.
你们怎么找到...
How did you find...
你们要对我做什么
What are you going to do to me?
就是想问你些问题
Just wanna ask you a few questions.
关于这个的
About this.
天呐  是明星号
Dear God, that's The Star.
-我的船  -本该是的
- That's my ship! - Well, it should've been.
我们了解它的事
Yeah, we know all about her.
我们觉得你会想见一个人
We figured there's someone you'd wanna meet.
你好  加文
Hello, Gavin.
你跟我父亲年轻时一个样
You look just like my father when he was young.
加文  这是罗威娜
Gavin, meet Rowena,
你奶奶
your grandmother.
我奶奶
My grandmother?
她不可能还活着
She can't have be alive.
严格讲  你也不该还活着
Well, technically, dude, neither can you.
难以置信
Amazin'.
父亲跟我说它在风暴中沉没了
Father told me she'd gone down in the storm
完蛋了
and that was the end of her.
如果你也在船上  也会一起完蛋
The end of you, too, if you'd been aboard.
加文  你能跟我们说说其他
Gavin, what can you tell us about the other passengers
原本要渡洋的乘客吗
who were supposed to make the crossing?
都是普通人
Ordinary folk.
店主  农夫  一个医生  一个老师
Storekeepers, farmers, a doctor, a teacher.
老师
A teacher?
嗯
Aye.
艾洛维女士
Mistress Allaway.
她是我们村大部分人的老师
She taught most of us in the village.
这是船上找到的所有东西吗
This everyveing they found aboard?
对  你如果认得什么告诉我们
Yes. Let us know if you recognize anything.
不认得
Nope.
Nope. ‭
那是麦卡伦先生的钩子
There's Mr. MacCallum's hook.
他没有手
Had no hand, you see.
不认得
No.
老天爷
Oh, sweet Lord.
是那吊坠
It's the locket.
吊坠
The locket?
是我买的
I bought it myself.
是给我的菲奥娜的礼物
It was a gift for my Fiona.
亲爱的  你还有个女朋友吗
Darlin', you had a wee girlfriend?
看啊  六个月前加入展品的
Look at this. Added to the exhibit six months ago.
菲奥娜·邓肯
Fiona Duncan,
我的挚爱
the love of my life.
她得知我要去美国时
When she found out I was going to America,
非要我带上她
nothing would do but I take her with me.
我告诉她那太危险了
I told her it was too dangerous.
这怎么会在这儿  如果你没登船
How did it get here? If you didn't board the ship,
她应该也没了吧
then she wouldn't have either, right?
我不知道
I don't know.
那可怕的晚上
That terrible night...
我正在收拾行李  准备走
I was packing, ready to leave.
菲奥娜说她会来见我
Fiona said she was going to come see me,
再求我一次带上她
beg me one more time to take her along.
显然  我没登上船
Obviously, I never made it to the ship.
你说什么  请进
What's that, you say? Come in?
那我就不客气了
Don't mind if I do.
如果菲奥娜那晚来了
If Fiona came that night,
我当时已经不在了
I was gone.
那她会以为你没带她就走了
And she would've thought that you left without her.
天呐  她肯定是自己偷偷上了船
Dear God, she must've smuggled herself aboard.
她真的会做出那样的事吗
Would she really have done something like that?
她意志很坚定
Iron will, that one.
她会躲起来  直到船行驶到海上
She'd have stayed hidden until they were at sea
不能调头
and there was no turnin' back.
那她会死掉  又愤怒又心碎
And she would've died, pissed as hell and heartbroken.
嗯  未竟心愿
Yeah, unfinished business.
这个鬼魂大概与吊坠相连
We got a ghost probably tethered to the locket.
鬼魂
A ghost?
我的菲奥娜成了鬼魂
My Fiona's a ghost?
好吧  这玩意在哪
All right, where is this thing?
121号展品
Item 121.
-121  -对
- 121? - ‭Yeah.
好
All right.
萨姆
Sam?
-怎么  -它不见了
- What? - It's gone.
那么...
So...
那杯酒...
about that drink...
我还是算了
I'm good, actually.
你的儿子
Your sons...
我相信他们是很不错的
I'm... sure they're fine lads and all,
但你最好还是
but it might be best if you were to...
跟他们稍稍脱离一点
disengage from them a bit.
脱离
Disengage?
这份工作
This work.
非常辛苦  而且必须被放在首位
It's demanding and it must come first.
记录者就是我的家庭
The Men of Letters is my family.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对我而言  没什么比我的家庭更重要
Nothing comes before my family, not with me.
是吗
Really?
还是说那是你想去相信的
Or is that just what you want to believe?
你跟他们说话时表现得不一样
You're different when you talk to them.
更温柔
Softer.
更软弱
Weaker.
不是羞辱你  只是我的观察
Not an insult, just an observation.
但你猎魔时  玛丽
But when you hunt, Mary...
你是我见过的最棒的之一
you're one of the best I've ever seen.
你或许会扮演好妈妈
Now you might play at being the good mummy,
但你深陷其中时
but when you're in the thick of it,
只有手中的武器和空气中的血腥味
nothing but a blade in your hand and blood in the air,
那才是真正的你
that's the real you,
最棒的你
the best you.
我觉得你也清楚
And I think you know it.
我觉得这让你非常害怕
And I think that scares the hell out of you.
抱歉打扰  奥乔亚博士
Sorry to interrupt, Dr. Ochoa.
我们在查看沉船展品
We've been looking through the shipwreck exhibit
与凶案的联系
in connection with the murders.
似乎有件展品遗失了
There seems to be an item missing.
嗯
Yeah.
这里  121号  一个吊坠
It's right here. 121. It's a locket.
不可能  它在封闭的展柜里
That's not possible. It's in a sealed case.
我们知道  女士  但我们到处找了
We know, ma'am, but -- but we've looked everywhere.
真的不见了
It's definitely gone.
这几天里又来过老师带队的
Have one of those, um, student tours been through here
学生参观团队吗
the last couple of days, the ones led by the teachers?
是的  昨天就有一个
Yes, there was one yesterday.
他们是哪来的
And where are they from?
潘布鲁克女子日校
The Pembroke Day School for Girls.
(潘布鲁克女子日校)
我要去睡了
That's it for me.
喝杯酒吗
How 'bout a glass of wine?
好  我再读到一篇网上抄来的《荒凉山庄》论文
Yeah. I read one more Internet-bought paper on "Bleak House,"
就要叫起来了
I'll scream.
又来
Again?
配电盘又坏了
The panel?
它死了吗
Is it dead?
-是啊  死很久了  -什么
- Yeah. Has been for a long time. - ‭What?
-那是鬼魂  -盐弹只能暂时拖住它
- It was a ghost. - The rock salt only slowed it down.
我们得搞清楚它是不是菲奥娜
All right, we gotta figure out if this was Fiona.
开始吧
So, show time.
不安的灵魂
"O restless spirit,
向我显形吧
make thy presence known to me."
菲奥娜
Fiona?
是我  加文
It is I, Gavin.
你的加文
Your Gavin.
我必须跟你谈谈
I must speak with you.
菲奥娜
Fiona.
加文
Gavin.
你抛弃了我
You abandoned me.
你...你去哪了
You...Where were you?
我去了你家  我...
I came to your room. I --
不是我的错  我被送去了别处
It wisnae my fault. I was sent somewhere else.
我躲在了明星号上
I hid myself aboard The Star,
你却不在上面保护我
and you wernnae there to protect me.
船员
The crew,
他们来嘲笑我  鄙夷我
they came to scorn me and mock me
还不止
and worse.
他们惨无人道地蹂躏了我
Use me in a way no woman should be used.
其他乘客
The other passengers...
没人帮你吗
Did no one help you?
都束手旁观
All did nothing.
还有艾洛维女士  我们的老师
And Mistress Allaway, our teacher?
她说我向你投怀送抱  所以活该有此下场
She said I deserved it for throwin' myself at you.
老师  他们自称爱孩子
Teachers -- they claim to love children,
却背叛他们
and then they betray them.
我不能惩罚她  但其他人会偿还她的孽债
I cou'dna punish her, but others will pay her debt.
她在船上生不如死
Her life aboard that ship was so unbearable,
所以她把死视为了解脱
she felt death would be a relief.
我曾经认识的善良少女现在成了一心复仇的鬼魂
But the sweet maid I knew is now a spirit bent on revenge.
我们都同意得阻止菲奥娜
So we agree Fiona has to be stopped.
我们不能烧了她的遗骨
We can't burn her bones.
那在大西洋海底呢
They're at the bottom of the Atlantic.
可以毁掉吊坠  但是
Could destroy the locket. Then again,
她可能还跟船上其他的东西有连接
she might also be tethered to something else on the ship.
不管怎样  她杀死的可怜人都无法复生了
Either way, nothing can bring back the poor people she killed.
其实  或许有办法
Actually, there might be a-a way
修复一切
to fix pretty much everything.
什么办法
What?
让菲奥娜不会变成鬼魂
Keep Fiona from going Casper in the first place.
是啊  如果她不是愤怒孤独地
Yeah. There's no reason for her to be a ghost
一个人在船上  也就不会变鬼了
if she's not angry and alone... on the ship.
你们不是想干扰时间流吧
You don't intend to tamper with the flow of time do you?
这要看加文的
That's up to Gavin.
我们不是想找解决办法吗  这就是
Look, we're lookin' for a fix here, okay? This is it.
我们让他登上船
We get him aboard that ship,
他跟菲奥娜一起出海  保护她
he travels with Fiona, keeps her safe.
然后死掉  这就是你们的解决办法
And go to his death. That's your solution?
我没说这个很好
I didn't say it was the fun one, okay?
这是唯一的办法  你很清楚
Just the one, and you know it.
那样历史也不会被扭曲了
And it would keep history intact.
我也是这么想的
I...was thinki'' the same thing.
我爱她  她爱我
I loved her. She loved me.
这一切发生都是因为这个
That's the only reason any of this happened.
我可以让她不必蒙受困住了她的噩梦
I can spare her the nightmare she's trapped in.
我本来也无法融入这里
I cannae say I ever fit here.
在这里  我是孤独的
Here, I'm alone.
菲奥娜和我
Fiona and me,
我们可以永世在一起
we'll spend eternity together.
绝不可能
Never gonna happen.
就因为笨蛋和笨笨蛋
Just 'cause Dim and Dimmer here
无法把自己的家人留在一个维度里
can't keep their own family all in the same dimension,
不代表他们可以动我的家人
doesn't mean they can mess with mine!
父亲  我想这么做
Father, I want to do this.
你需要的是健身房会员卡
What you want is a gym membership,
猫头鹰餐厅的酒水半价时段  和小熊队门票
happy hour at Hooters, and Cubs tickets --
那些都只在这里有
none of which are available anywhere else but here.
我已经决定了
I've made up my mind.
那你为什么叫我来
Then why did you call me?
你找他了
You called him?
为了道别
To say goodbye.
让他去吧  费格斯
Let him go, Fergus.
别插嘴
Butt out.
费格斯  他跟我们不一样
Fergus, he's not like us.
他有信仰
He believes in things.
让他做他认为正确的事
Let him do what he believes is right.
[咒语]
母亲
Mother...
你该死
Damn you.
对不起  父亲
I'm sorry, Father.
(潘布鲁克女子日校)
好了吗
That soup yet?
快了
Almost.
准备好了吗
You ready?
动手吧
Do it.
准备好了吗  加文
Ready to do this, Gavin?
你确定这能成功
You're positive this will work?
从未试过
Never done it before.
但我们爷爷做过  阿比顿也做过
But our granddad did. And Abaddon.
罗威娜把咒语做了改动  好让你用
And Rowena tweaked the spell so that you could use it.
好了
All right.
应该行了
I think that's it.
真不好受啊
This is a tough one.
你是个好人  加文
You're a good guy, Gavin.
谢谢
Thank you.
希望
Hopefully...
这是最好的办法
this is all for the best.
送他去吧
Beam him up, Scotty.
[咒语]
(无结果)
女校的老师都回去工作了
So the teachers at the girls' school are all back to work.
就好像什么都没发生
It's like nothing ever happened.
俄亥俄州的被害人都查到了
That's all the victims in Ohio.
麻省的案子也查不到
Well, no mention of the Massachusetts murder either.
没有菲奥娜  没有愤怒鬼魂
no Fiona, no angry ghost.
看来历史归位了
Looks like history is back on track.
谢谢  加文
Thank you, Gavin.
-妈妈  -哎呦
- Mom! - ‭Well, well!
好久不见
‭It has been a while.
好久  好久  好久  好久了
A long, long... long, long, long, long while.
他就是矫情  你也知道
Yeah, all right. He's dramatic, as you know.
他是想说  我们想你了
What he meant to say was, we missed you.
很高兴你回来了
Glad you're back.
汉堡包  啤酒
Burgers. Beer.
美味
Yum. ‭
原谅你了
Forgiven.
你都干什么了
Whatcha been up to?
慢跑  太极  冥想
Jogging, tai chi, meditation.
融化食人怪的大脑
Melting rugaru brains.
M-m-melting rugaru brains?
这话没法委婉地说  我就直说了
There's no easy way to say it, so I'm just gonna say it.
我一直
I have sort of...
在跟英国记录者合作
been working with the British Men of Letters.
你...什么
M-- You -- you, uh... you what?
妈妈
Mom...
我们
we, um...
我们跟他们有过节
we have a-a history with them.
我知道  萨姆
I know, Sam.
这个决定很艰难
And it was a hard decision.
但他们在做好事
But they're doing good work.
我帮他们救了人  很多人
I have helped them save people, a lot of people.
我们可以向他们学习
We can learn from them.
别摆那副表情
Do not give me the face.
-什么表情  -你知道的
- What face? - You know the face.
-没什么表情  -就是那个
- There's no face. - That's the face.
妈妈  我们有自己的工具
Mom, we have our own tool kit,
而且也挺好用
and it works just fine.
因为一些明显的原因
A-and for obvious reasons,
比如折断的肋骨  和烧伤的脚
like broken ribs and burnt feet...
我们不信任那些英国人
We don't trust the Brits.
那我们怎么办
So where does that leave us?
和以往一样
Same as always.
我们是一家人
Family.
听我说完
Just hear me out.
求你们
Please.
你做的事
What you did...
就算对你  也太过分了
A low, even for you.
那不对
Wasn't right. ‭
你会知道什么是对的
And you would know what's right?
我知道你有个丑陋  讨厌  恶意的理由
I know there's an ugly, rancid, spiteful reason
让我的儿子  你的孙子  去送死
why you sent my son, your grandson, to his death.
我想知道是什么
I wanna know what it is.
他是个好孩子
He was a lovely boy.
我知道你以你的方式在乎他
And in your own lizard way, I know you cared for him.
就像我在乎奥斯卡
just as I cared for Oskar.
奥斯卡
Oskar.
我爱他胜过你的孩子
The child I loved more than you.
你为了移除该隐血印逼我杀死他
The boy you made me kill in order to remove the Mark of Cain.
所以加文做的是正确的事什么的
So that was all drivel you were spewing
只是你瞎说的
about Gavin doing the right thing.
的确是正确的事
It was the right thing.
对于加文或许是的  对我绝对是
Maybe for Gavin, certainly for me.
让我看到你蒙受丧子之痛
It allowed me to watch you suffer the loss of a child.
报复
Payback.
我是你母亲  亲爱的
I'm your mother, dear.
还有谁更能碾碎你的小心脏
Who better to crush your shriveled heart?
大衮
Dagon.